Guide to the John Jacob Coss Papers
Rare Book and Manuscript Library Columbia University Libraries
John Jacob Coss Papers
1908-1952.
Coss, John J. (John Jacob), 1884-1940.
6 linear ft (ca.5,600 items in 14 boxes).
Columbia University. Rare Book and Manuscript Library, New York, NY.
MS#0286
4079677
This collection contains correspondence, manuscripts, documents, notebooks, and photographs of John Jacob Coss, professor of Philosophy.
Biographical Note
Moore Collegiate Professor of Philosophy at Columbia University.
Scope and Content
Correspondence, manuscripts, documents, notebooks, and photographs including: Correspondence with Columbia faculty, such as John Dewey and Robert Lynd; Columbia University matters, especially his participation in the introduction of the Contemporary Civilization courses; Correspondence sent to him as Director of the Summer Session, 1919-1939; Personal correspondence; Much correspondence relating to the Ropsenwald Fund for Negro Education; Manuscripts and typescripts of addresses, articles, and other writings; Notes and other materials arranged by subject; and 17 of his notebooks kept while a student at Columbia, Union Theological Seminary, and the University of Heidelberg.
1984 addition: Travel journals in the form of typescript copies of letters, photographs, postcards, and memorabilia; typescript copies of Coss' personal correspoondence from 1909 to 1920; and Columbia related material, chiefly Camp Columbia, 1919-1920, including photographs. These items are mounted on sheets of paper.
Arrangement
Selected materials cataloged; remainder arranged.
This collection is arranged in three series:
Series I: Correspondence
Series II: Papers
Series III: 1984 Addition
Subjects
Columbia University.; Dewey, John, 1859-1952.; Lynd, Robert Staughton, 1892-1970.; African Americans--History.; Civilization.; Culture.; Philosophers.; Addresses.; Articles.; Bibliographies.; Journals.; Notebooks.; Photographs.; Surveys.; College teachers.
Acquisition
M-1984 Dilks, Mrs John H. Gift
Transferred from Columbia; Gift of Mrs John Hyland Dilks, 1984.
Access Restrictions
The following boxes are located off-site: Boxes 4-14. You will need to request this material from the Rare Book and Manuscript Library at least twenty-four (24) hours in advance to use the collection in the Rare Book and Manuscript Library reading room.
This collection has no restrictions.
- Series I: Correspondence
  - A-G (Box 1)
  - H-R (Box 2)
  - S-end (Box 3)
- Series II: Papers
  - Addresses and articles (Box 4)
  - Subject Folders
    - Columbia College
      - General (Box 5)
      - Religious Work (Box 5)
    - Columbia Spectator (Box 5)
    - Columbia University - Upper College (Box 5)
    - Commonwealth Fund (Box 5)
    - Contemporary Civilization Course
      - budget (Box 5)
      - Coast Guard Academy (Box 5)
      - field trips budget (Box 5)
      - general (Box 5)
      - modern marriage (Box 5)
      - syllabus illustrations (Box 5)
    - Coss, John Jacob
      - bibliography of his writings (Box 5)
      - Military service (1918-1919) (Box 5)
      - obituaries & memorials (Box 5)
      - photographs (Box 5)
      - school records (Box 5)
        - (Wabash College) (Box 5)
        - (Union Theological Seminary) (Box 5)
    - Employee management (bibliography) (Box 5)
    - Flint Goodridge Hospital, New Orleans (Box 5)
    - Henderson, Donald (Box 5)
    - Orientation course (University of Minnesota) (Box 5)
    - Personnel survey - 1927-1928 (Box 5)
    - Rosenwald Fund for Negro Education
      - General (Box 5)
      - miscellaneous correspondence (Box 5)
    - Seth Low Junior College (Box 5)
    - 17 notebooks - 1907-1911 (Box 6)
- Series III: 1984 Addition
  - Personal Correspondence, 1909-1920 (Box 7)
  - Travel Journals
    - Parts I- IV (1924-1927) (Box 8)
    - Parts V-VII (1927-1931) (Box 9)
    - Parts VIII-XI (1931) (Box 10)
    - Parts XII-XV (1931-1936) (Box 11)
    - Parts XI-XIX (1930s) (Box 12)
    - Parts XX-XXIII (1930s) (Box 13)
    - Parts XXIV-XXVI (1938) and Columbia-Related Materials (Box 14)